PRINCEWILL UZOCHUKWU DURU

09019204780

duruprincewilluzochukwu@gmail.com

No 6, Ijoola Street, Maryland, Ikeja, Lagos State https://princewillduru.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

Creative Front End Developer with 2 years of experience in building and maintaining web applications. Proficient in HTML, CSS, TAILWINDCSS, and JAVASCRIPT, using a modern library such as REACTJS.

Knowledge of REACT tools including REACT.JS, WEBPACK, and REDUX

Knowledge of of javascript testing framework such as JEST..

Understanding of the integration of backend Javascript libraries such as NODEJS.

Experience in the integration of NoSQL databases such as FIREBASE.

Knowledge of version control such as GIT.

Problem solving skills.

Good interpersonal skills to build good working relationship.

EDUCATION

Rufus Giwa Polytechnic, Owo, Ondo State	2017 – 2019
HND In Estate Management and Valuation	
Rufus Giwa Polytechnic, Owo, Ondo State	2014 – 2016
OND In Estate Management and Valuation	
High Focus International School	2007 - 2013
Secondary School Certificate (WAEC)	

WORK EXPERIENCE

Willtta | Marketplace for student

2022

- Built a marketplace application for students with reusable components using Reactjs and Redux(state management tool), which is used to solve problems inherent among students in Nigerian institutions.
- Built the MVP to test run the product.
- Built the search engine that fetch data from the database on request..
- Managed user data using Realtime Database.
- Stored data on the database using Firebase/Firestore.
- Created collections that saved user data on the database and fetched those data on request.

Lfood web store | E-commerce Food Store Application

2021

- Built an E-commerce store for food ordering and delivery using React and Redux which offers payment functionality.
- Worked to give the web application a great user friendly web pages and user experience.
- Managed user data using Realtime Database.
- Stored users order on the database using Firebase/Firestore..

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT AND CERTIFICATIONS

FreeCodeCamp
Responsive Web Design
FreeCodeCamp
JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

Aug 2021

Nov 2021

LEADERSHIP

President 2019-2019

Estate Management and Valuation Department (EMSA), Rufus Giwa Polytechnic Chapter

- Facilitate, promote and negotiate good welfare for the students
- Organize meetings with the head of the department on issues regarding the department
- Managed and executed projects for the department.

Community Development Coordinator

2021-2022

National Youth Service Corps, Itesiwaju, Oyo State

- Organized the community development service for the community
- Worked with the Local Government Inspector and community heads on issues relating to the communities' development
- Facilitated, promoted, and negotiated community development projects
- Planned and monitored empowerment programs.

SKILLS & HOBBIES

Technical skills: Vast knowledge in the use of Front-end technologies such as HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Bootstrap, Tailwindcss, Reactjs, Nodejs, Redux, Git, jest

Organizational Skills: Creative thinking, Problem Solving, Excellent Communication, and Team

Management, Time Management, Research Orientation.

Hobbies: Playing video games, Gymnastics, and sports.

REFERENCES

Mr. Falona, K.

Lecturer, Department of Estate Management and Valuation, Akure, Ondo State. 08066154327

Mr. Omale

Life Press, Lagos State 08158190071